# **Andre Uzamurengera**

KG 565 ST, Kigali (+250)-788-687-281

## uzandre12@gmail.com

A software and data engineer with more 6 years' experience providing IT solutions to solve complex problems. Trained more than 1500 students of University of Rwanda in programming and continue to focus on software engineering, data science & computer networks when advancing in my career.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### **Data Scientist in Bank Supervision**

Jan 2022 - present

National Bank of Rwanda

- Cleaning Data identifying, assessing, and resolving any data quality issues, developing, and executing data cleanup measures.
- Extracting, manipulating, exploring data using quantitative, statistical, and visualization tools.
- Building algorithms, predictive models, and dashboards that get deployed in the form of products, policy, or scientific research.

#### Assistant lecturer in Computer Science

University of Rwanda

2015 - 2022

- Developing and teaching modules of computer science
- Working with the faculty to deliver lectures and making sure that students understand the concepts taught
- Enhancing programming and networking skills of more than 1000 students in the University of Rwanda

#### **Software Engineer (Practicum Project)**

Jan 2019 - May 2019

Rwanda Information Society Authority (RISA)

- Developed an Android application for the Government Command Center commonly known as GCC.
- Analyzed the GCC database structure and redesigned a proper database that could solve the identified issues.
- Recommended the RISA team on want could be done to fix all other issues in the GCC.

#### **Graduate Teaching Assistant**

2018 - 2020

Carnegie Mellon University

- Preparing weekly recitations, assignments, labs, and guizzes along with solutions for the assignments
- Grading homework assignments, labs, quizzes and assigning grades before deadlines
- Holding office hours to help students grasp the concepts taught in class and answers their questions about the course

#### Software developer intern May 2018 - Aug 2018

RURA

- Developed the Integrated e-Ticketing System for all transport companies in Rwanda
- Analyzed data from transport companies and presented key information on a friendly dashboard that helps RURA to get insights about transport

#### EDUCATION

#### CARNEGIE MELLON UNIVERSITY AFRICA

2017 - 2019

#### Master of Science in Information Technology

Concentrations: Software Engineering, Telecommunication & Computer Networks

#### UNIVERSITY OF RWANDA IN PARTNERSHIP WITH ÖREBRO UNIVERSITY

2016 - 2018

#### Master of Science in Information systems

Concentrations: e-Government

NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF RWANDA

2010 - 2013

## Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Systems

Concentrations: Software Engineering & Networking

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Mobile applications development certified by the Kenya National Commission for UNESCO.
- Artificial Intelligence Analyst certified by IBM
- Programming languages: NodeJS, Java, Python, NativeScript, PHP, C/C++, JavaScript and MATLAB.
- Building Ethernet network using routers and switches certified by CISCO
- Took courses such as Fundamental of Software Development, Data Structure & Algorithms, Advanced Database Systems, Data Inference and AppliedMachine Learning, Data Analytics, Advanced Programming (Java), Software Defined Radio, Information Security, Vulnerability Assessment& Testing, Fundamental of Telecommunication Networks, Information System Evaluation etc.